Walter and Naomi Rosenblum Collection of Photography and Photographic History MSS.556
Fales Library and Special Collections
Walter and Naomi Rosenblum Collection of Photography and Photographic History
1860-2018
1940-2014
Fales Library and Special Collections
Rosenblum, Walter, 1919-2006
Rosenblum, Naomi
Rosenblum, Nina
MSS.556
91.89 Linear Feet 87 manuscript boxes, 3 half manuscript boxes, 4 flat boxes, 11 oversized flat boxes, 7 media boxes, 3 custom photo boxes, 2 custom book boxes, 1 CD box, and 7 flat file folders
25.55 Gigabytes in 18 computer files
10 VHS
11 sound tape reels
43 audiocassettes
3 Hi8
1 DAT
3 MiniDV
2.73 Gigabytes in unprocessed digital files
Walter A. Rosenblum (1919–2006) was an American photographer and member of the Photo League, a cooperative of New York based photographers focused on socially conscious photography. Walter served in World War II and photographed the D-Day landings at Normandy in 1944. He was also the first Allied photographer to enter the liberated Dachau concentration camp. Naomi Rosenblum (1925-2021) was a historian of photography and wrote about individual photographers including Lewis Hine and Paul Strand. She also published several monographs including, A World History of Photography and A History of Women Photographers. The Walter and Naomi Rosenblum Collection of Photography and Photographic History (dated 1860-2018) consists of materials created and collected by the Rosenblums documenting their careers as photographers and historians of photography. Materials in this collection include articles, magazines, and newspaper coverage of Walter's photographic career; catalogs and other ephemera from exhibitions; scrapbooks of Walter's career and his student's photographs; Walter's master photographic prints; and panels from the traveling exhibition They Fight With Cameras: Walter Rosenblum in World War II from D-Day to Dachau. The collection also documents Naomi's career as a historian of photography and includes correspondence, research files, examples of historical photographic processing techniques like daguerreotypes and tintypes, as well as original writings on individual photographers (including Lewis Hine and Paul Strand) and the history of photography in general. Additionally, the collection contains materials documenting the activities of The Photo League in the 1930s-1940s and the Rosenblum's personal items like desk calendars and awards.
Scope and Contents
The Walter and Naomi Rosenblum Collection of Photography and Photographic History (dated 1860-2018) consists of materials created and collected by the Rosenblums documenting their careers as photographers and historians of photography. Materials in this collection include articles, magazines, and newspaper coverage of Walter's photographic career; catalogs and other ephemera from exhibitions; scrapbooks of Walter's career and his student's photographs; Walter's master prints; and panels from the traveling exhibition They Fight With Cameras: Walter Rosenblum in World War II from D-Day to Dachau. The collection also documents Naomi's career as a historian of photography and includes correspondence, research files, examples of historical photographic processing techniques like daguerreotypes and tintypes, as well as original writings on individual photographers (including Lewis Hine and Paul Strand) and the history of photography in general (particularly for her works A World History of Photography and A History of Women Photographers). Additionally, the collection contains materials documenting the activities of The Photo League in the 1930s-1940s. The collection also includes some audiovisual materials containing interviews with the Rosenblums, as well as born-digital items containing essay drafts and photographs.
The Walter and Naomi Rosenblum Collection of Photography and Photographic History also provides some insight about the Rosenblums' personal lives through postcards, personal correspondence, awards, desk calendars, personal photographs, address books, and Naomi's sketch pads. Some materials – mainly film posters – relating to their daughter Nina (a documentarian), can also be found within this collection.
Most of the materials in this collection are written in English, however there are also some items written in Russian, French, Italian, Chinese, and Japanese.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged into the following series and sub-series:
Series I: Naomi Rosenblum's Research Materials, Correspondence, Subject Files, and Lectures
Series II: Walter Rosenblum
Sub-series II.A: Master Prints
Sub-series II.B: Exhibition Materials
Sub-series II.C: Lecture and Publication Materials
Series III: The Photo League
Series IV: Walter and Naomi Rosenblum Personal Materials
Within each series and sub-series, some materials have been arranged alphabetically and/or grouped together thematically, when possible.
Conditions Governing Access
Box 89 contains legal documents that are restricted. The remaining materials in the collection are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Naomi Rosenblum in November 2018, January 2019, and December 2021. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2018.116, 2019.007, and 2021.040. In February 2024, Nina Rosenblum donated an accretion; the accession number associated with this gift is 2024.016.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Separated Materials
Camera equipment was separated from the archival collection. Some pieces were transferred to the Tisch School of the Arts Department of Photography and Imaging for teaching purposes while the remaining were returned to the donor.
During processing, a large selection of commercially published books, a Lewis Hine calendar, and various personal correspondence including holiday cards and birth announcements were removed from the collection and either returned to the donor or transfered to Bobst library.
Biographical Note
Walter A. Rosenblum (1919–2006) was an American photographer born in New York City. He was introduced to documentary photography early in his career as a member of the Photo League, which was a cooperative of New York based photographers focused on socially conscious photography. While part of the League, he became friends with notable photographers Paul Strand and Lewis Hine. Walter served as the Photo League's secretary, became editor of the organization's journal (Photo Notes), and in 1941, he became president of the Photo League. During World War II, Walter was a member of the U.S. Army Signal Corp Combat Unit. He photographed the American D-Day landings at Omaha Beach in Normandy in 1944, filmed General Patton's advance across France and Germany, and finally, he was one of the first Allied photographers to enter the liberated Dachau concentration camp. After the war, Walter began teaching photography at Brooklyn College's Art Department. He also taught for several years at Cooper Union and Yale's Summer School of Music and Art. During this time, Walter produced several photographic series focused upon Haiti, Europe, East Harlem, and the South Bronx. Over the course of his career, Walter Rosenblum was the recipient of the Guggenheim Foundation Fellowship, a National Endowment of the Arts Grants, a Simon Weisenthal Award, and other distinctions. He also received an honorary doctoral degree from the University of Maryland in 1986.
Naomi Rosenblum (1925-2021) was a historian of photography born in Los Angeles. She wrote about important individual photographers including Lewis Hine, Paul Strand, and Alfred Stieglitz, as well as published several monographs including, A World History of Photography and A History of Women Photographers. After receiving her Bachelor of Arts in fine arts from Brooklyn College in 1948, Naomi completed her Masters in fine arts at CUNY Graduate Center in 1975. She went on to earn her doctorate in art history and the history of photography in 1978 at CUNY Graduate Center. Her doctoral dissertation examined the early work of Paul Strand circa 1920 to 1932. During her career, Naomi curated several museum exhibitions including the traveling exhibit "A History of Women Photographers" in 1997, "Documenting a Myth: The South As Seen By Three Women Photographers" in 1997 at the Douglas F. Cooley Memorial Art Gallery (Reed College), and "America and Lewis Hine, a retrospective of the work of Lewis Hine at the Brooklyn Museum" (1977). The latter exhibit was co-curated with her husband, Walter. She also gave lectures about the history of photography across the United States and abroad.
Walter and Naomi Rosenblum met while he was teaching at Brooklyn College. They were married in 1949 and went on to have two daughters, Nina and Lisa. On May 4, 1998, both Naomi and Walter Rosenblum were awarded the International Center of Photography's Lifetime Achievement Award.
Related Materials
For more information about Walter Rosenblum, see Walter Rosenblum Unitarian Service Committee Papers (TAM.471) and Walter Rosenblum Photographs of Spanish Refugees (PHOTOS.249).
Appraisal
One disc, Fundacion Santander Central Hispano y PHE05 presentan la exposición Callie Mayor, was deaccessioned because it could not be imaged.
Photography -- History; Photographers -- United States.; Photojournalism.; Women photographers; Photographers.; France.; New York (N.Y.).; Haiti; World War, 1939-1945.; Photographs.; Correspondence.; Research notes.; Scrapbooks.; Exhibition Announcements.; Books.; Sketchbooks.; Rosenblum, Walter, 1919-2006; Rosenblum, Walter, 1919-2006; Rosenblum, Naomi; Rosenblum, Naomi; Rosenblum, Nina; Rosenblum, Nina; Strand, Paul, 1890-1976; Hine, Lewis Wickes, 1874-1940; Photo League; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986
- Series I: Naomi Rosenblum's Research Materials, Correspondence, Subject Files, and Lectures, 1860-2018 (inclusive), 1963-2014 (bulk); 21.38 Linear Feet in 49 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, 4 oversized flat boxes, and 1 flat file folder
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains Naomi Rosenblum's research notes, correspondence, bibliography lists, lectures, books, articles, newspaper clippings, and photographs relating to the following topics: the history of photography and women photographers, a world history of photography, social photography, Paul Strand, Alfred Stieglitz, Lewis Hine, the Photo League, and examples historical photographic techniques including prints, daguerreotypes, ambrotypes, and tintypes.
  Commercially published books used by Naomi Rosenblum as research materials were removed from the collection.
  Arrangement
  Within this series, correspondence has been arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The remaining materials have been grouped together thematically, when possible.
  - A History of Women Photographs Press Clippings, 1985, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Naomi/Vita, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History of Photog Mag, 1976-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Script WP, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rights Agreement (Women Photographers), 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Review: American Art by Evan H. Turner, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Art Journal/Review, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Revisions for A.W.H., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History of Photography Group, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Vision is my dwelling place, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - World History Photography Notes, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - World History Photography Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Corr: Abbeville/Katie Kahn/Publicity/Nancy/Misc, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - AHWP CDROM, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Kraszna-Krausz, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - A - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1995-1998, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1, Box 38)
  - B - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1985, 1990-2000, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 2, Box 38)
  - C- Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1988, 1990-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Box 38)
  - D - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1983-1984, 1987-2004 (Box 2, Folder 4, Box 38)
  - E - Correspondence, 1970-1990; 1985, 1988, 1995-2001, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 5, Box 38)
  - F - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1977-1987, 1990-2000, 2008, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 6, Box 38)
  - G - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1984, 1990-2003 (Box 2, Folder 7, Box 38)
  - H - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1985, 1988, 1990-2000, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 8, Box 38)
  - I - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1990, 1995, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9, Box 38)
  - J - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1991-1993, 1997-1998, 2000-2003 (Box 2, Folder 10, Box 38)
  - K- Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1976, 1984, 1988-2005, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 11, Box 38)
  - L - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1984, 1990-2002, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 12, Box 39, Folder 1)
  - M - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1985-2014 (Box 2, Folder 13, Box 39, Folder 2)
  - N - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1991-1999, 2001-2002, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 14, Box 39, Folder 3)
  - O - Correspondence, 1970-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - P - Correspondence, 1970-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Q - Correspondence, 1985, 1989-1999, 2004 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - R - Correspondence, 1964-1989; 1984, 1990-1999 (Box 2, Folder 17, Box 39, Folder 5)
  - S - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1984-1986, 1989-1993, 1996-2000, 2006, 2014-2015, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 18, Box 39, Folder 6)
  - T - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1985, 1990-2001 (Box 2, Folder 19, Box 40, Folder 1)
  - U - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1993-2003 (Box 2, Folder 20, Box 40, Folder 2)
  - V - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1993-2003 (Box 2, Folder 21, Box 40, Folder 2)
  - W - Correspondence, 1970-1989;1985-1996, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 22, Box 40, Folder 3)
  - XYZ - Correspondence, 1970-1989; 1982, 1989-1993, 1998, 2000-2006 (Box 2, Folder 23, Box 40, Folder 4)
  - AWHOP Revisions, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - AWHOP Rev Loose Ends, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photographs into Printer's Ink, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - GEH - Meeting, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - NYPL Photography Panel Tickets, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Modern Spirit: American Painting 1908-1935, Arts Council of Great Britain (article on photography by Naomi Rosenblum), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - AHOWP/Covers, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Lectures, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Uconn Lecture (Wed 3/9), undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sevavezza Talk, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Articles about Photography, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - St. Louis Art Museum, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Straight Photog- F64/Akron, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - University of Ct. (Garner), 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Women Seeing Women, WW Norton; Mairs, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Spilimbergo/Padua, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - San Diego, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Port Wash, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Photo Historical Society Lecture + Info, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Photo Espana 99 - Cards, Addresses, Tel + Fax Nos., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Photo Espana, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Oxford U Press - Robin Lenman, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - O'Keeffe/Stieg (Lynes, Naef), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Oregon/Reed Coll. Show, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - NPPA - Talk (Chicago), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Newark Mus. (Nettleton), 2006 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Milwaukee, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Modotti for Pierpaolo, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - ISSF (Italian History Institute - Morello), 2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Lang/Painted Photos, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Glauber/Watson-Schutze, 2004-2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Getty Notes/Invite, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - German Piece - The Other America Book/Exhibition, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Exposure, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Encyc of NYC Changes, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Encycl. Brittanica, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Currier (Gibbs), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - David Levi Strauss re: Photo Criticism, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cornell, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chrysler Museum, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - CCP: Tucson, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Camera Images of Labor: Past and Present (Naomi and Walter Rosenblum), undated (Box 5, Folder 5, Box 37, Folder 17)
  - AIPAD/Marks, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Akron, Seeing Straight, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Alex Bamberry & Photo, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Milwaukee Talk: c:\docu.pho\milw, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Alinari, 2000-2002 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - NR IBM Sima Psci/Lecture, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Article on Datar, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - B. Racker/St. Bonaventura, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Museum - Machine, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Canada/Toronto, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - City Images - Texts, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Center for Writers & Scholars, NYPL, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - MoMA Stats, 1990, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Akron/Pictorialism, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Oakland, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Middlemarch-American Photography, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - SPE - Bryn Mawr, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - St. Louis Art MU, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Oakland/Drew Johnson, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - George Eastman House, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - S.F. MoMA, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Calif. Pict Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Jacobi - Moortgat, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Italy, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Huntington W. Va, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Empire State, 1995, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - En Foco, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Padua, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Photography Exhibition Announcements, 1973-1979, 1983, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Oxford Companion, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Snapshot Proposal, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Chinese Photographs, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Chinese Photos, 1991, 1995, 1997, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Photography - Chinee (written materials, articles, etc…), 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Physical and Metaphysical in Architectural Criticism" (James Marston Fitch), 1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Photographers, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Chen Chang Fen, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lin Shaozhong/China, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Naomi - Misc Articles, 1984-1985, 1990, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "Women in Photography - A Decade of Women" (American Photo Magazine, Special Issue), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Mignon, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - ICP - Judging, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Articles & Talks on Social Photo, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Proposal for a History of Women Photographers, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Library Book Request Slips, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Research Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Research Notebooks, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Not the Photograph Alone" Research Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Programs, 1978, 1982, 1997, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Profily-Z Praci Mistru Ceskoslovenske Fotografie 1 (Josef Sudek), undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Profily-Z Praci Mistru Ceskoslovenske Fotografie 2 (Josef Ehm), undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The Other Amerika (Exh & Cat), 1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Italian - 20th Cent, 1984, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Photography - Social/Docu., 1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Photography, A.M. - Thirties-Paper, 1973, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Photography - Social Documentary, 1978, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Articles on Documentary Photography, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - List of Humanist Photographers, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Articles // Documentary, 1989, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - French Research Materials, 1981-1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Photography Documentary, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Postage Articles, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Black Photographers, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Photography - American - 1900 ~ 1935, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Photos of S. Africa, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Mexico, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Photography - Working People, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Afro-Amer Photog, 1981-1995 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Individual Social Photographers, 1985-1998 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Photojournalism, 1987, 1989, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Minneapolis, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Documentary Photog. Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Panel Discussion & Lecture Notes, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Research Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Curiosity and Compassion: A History of Social Documentation (Naomi Rosenblum) & Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Notes about Documentary Photography, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Research Notecards, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - American Indian, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Fernando Moleres - Child Labor, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Street Photog, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Photography Genre - Nineteenth Century, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Social Photo Stuff, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Early Documentation, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Photography - Documentation: British, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1930s-1940s, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1950s-1960s, 1996, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Humanist Photo Possiblities at Getty, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Italian Humanist, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Humanist, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Humanist Photography, 1980, 1997-2000 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
  - Doc Photo/Articles, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Italian Social Photog, 1990-1991, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The Camera Image in Social Action (N. Rosenblum) & Documentary Photography: A Historical Survey (N. Rosenblum), undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 1890's-1920's and Earlier, 1973, 1994, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Worker's Photography, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Worker/Photography Movement, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Ribalta, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Fotoit - La Fotografia in Italia Magazine, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Walter Ballhause, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Classic Photographs from the Brooklyn Museum Collection, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "The Art Historian and the Photographic Image" by Naomi & Walter Rosenblum in Art Journal, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Articles by Naomi Rosenblum, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Paul Strand, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Il Semana Paulista de Fotografia, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Staatliche Museum zu Berlin Hauptstadt der DDR, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - "Photography in Perspective: The First 150 Years" (Naomi Rosenblum), 1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Street & Studio: An Urban History of Photography (Tate Museum), 2007 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Helen Gee and the Limelight: A Pioneering Photography Gallery of the Fifties, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Corr - Naomi, 2008-2013 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Ansel Adams to PS, 1940, 1949, 1953-1959, 1962-1969, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Ansel Adams/Paul Strand Corresp/Copies, 1933, 1945, 1949, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Strand in Europe, 1993-1997 (Box 12, Folder 16)